Okay, so let's briefly discuss the ITTOs
of schedule management now.
Now again, when it comes to ITTO's input
tools and techniques and outputs,
you don't need to spend a huge amount of
time trying to memorize them.
Definitely do not memorize them.
You just need to have a basic
understanding.
You will not be necessarily asked.
At least not tons of
questions of what's an
input of this and
what's an output of that.
You just need to have a basic
understanding.
And all the important artifacts and tools
and techniques, we have separate videos on
all of the important ones that you need to
know.
Now, there are six processes again in
schedule management.
So there's a lot of ITTOs altogether.
The first process, right, just like any of
the knowledge areas, the very first
process always starts off with plan
knowledge area management, in this case,
schedule.
So plan schedule management
and the artifact that we
created in each of those
is always that management.
management plan.
So in this case, the schedule management
plan.
And the schedule management plan is
documenting how, right, determining the
approach to develop and control the
schedule.
How are we going to create the schedule?
And again, there's a
separate video outlining
the details of the
schedule management plan.
And then remember, as
a general rule and output
is this is the artifact
that we're creating.
And input is these are the artifacts that
we need, that we need to review.
view.
This is what we need to consider in order
to develop our schedule.
So first of all, in
order to, in this case,
how are we going to develop our schedule?
So we might be looking at our development
approach, for example.
Also the scope, what is the scope?
And how we develop in
the scope of the project can
determine how we're going
to develop the schedule.
And then our development approach.
What kind of methodology are we using?
Are we using an iterative?
Is it agile?
Right.
And then that can determine how we're
going to develop our schedule.
And then the common tools and techniques
across all of the plan management
processes, expert judgment, you need to
utilize their own knowledge and
experience, going to be analyzing data,
and then we're going to be having meetings.
Now, the next process then is define
activities.
So these are the basic ITTO then in
defined activities.
Well, first of all, let's think about
this.
Define activities.
Define activities is
the next stage, if you
like, from the work breakdown structure.
In WBS, you're breaking or
you are decomposing your
project down to the work
package in define activities.
It's the next stage where you are
decomposing, notice decomposition is a
tool and technique again,
so you're decomposing
your work package
into individual activities.
And so if it's individual activities,
the artifact is called the activity list.
These are the list of your activities.
Some of those activities are going to
define as a milestone.
So that's why we have milestone.
Now, we also see this as an output in
many, many processes, change requests.
And essentially what that is saying is,
you know, as you're executing your work,
you know, any process
that you perform, you
might need to go through a change control.
You might need to make some changes.
And so you might need to go through a
change control.
And that's why we see change requests as
an output for, you know, most processes.
Now, our starting point,
in order to develop our
activity, in order to figure
out what activities we need.
Remember, you can't do your schedule.
Your schedule is made up of your
activities.
So what's our consideration?
What do we need?
How do we know what activities we need?
Remember, one of the starting points is
going to be the work package.
Work package is made up of many
activities.
Where does the work package come from?
The work breakdown structure, which is
part of the scope baseline.
And so that's why one of the inputs here
is the scope baseline.
Another tool and technique,
rolling wave planning,
remember that's a type
of progressive elaboration.
Planning near-term items in detail,
longer term at a much more high level.
Now, once we've defined our activities,
then we can start sequencing them,
putting them in the proper order.
This is the first activity, this is the
next activity.
These activities can be run in parallel,
determining the optimum
order of the activities.
And essentially what we're creating is the
Schedule Network Diagram.
And then some of the consideration,
then, again, we need our activities.
We need to know what our activities are.
Other things to consider, right,
our tools and techniques here.
So one of the tools, and again, we have
separate videos on all of these tools.
Precedence diagramming method.
That uses a methodology
called Critical Path
Method, which is, again,
covered in separate videos.
Dependencies.
right so again covered in a separate video
so these are things like mandatory
dependency discretionary dependency and
that's also going to determine our finish
to start start to finish relationships and
so and so forth right so again with all
these tools and techniques we have
separate videos and all of them PMIS just
want to take a side step here project
management information system is a tool or
tools that you use to manage your project
all the different software tools so in
this case we're sequencing them we're
developing our schedule you're going to be
using some kind of software to develop
your schedule.
Now, also, as you're
identifying activities, you're going
to figure out how long these
activities are going to take.
So estimate activity duration,
that's the name of this process.
And then the Pimbox 6 output of that was
the duration estimate.
These are the tools and techniques that
you might be utilizing, and we're going to
have the separate videos and all of these,
right?
So these are all covered in separate
videos.
some of the input, what do we need to
create our estimate?
One of the key things
that impact your duration
estimate is availability
of your resources.
They're going to impact when you can
perform certain activities.
You need to use a machine.
That machine is being shared
amongst other team members,
sorry, amongst other teams
and amongst other business units.
Well, the availability of
that machine is going to
determine when you can
run those activities, right?
Those machines are resources.
So naturally, these resources then are
going to be an input, a starting point,
a consideration for determining when
you're going to be performing your
activities, your schedule, and then
duration estimates.
And then develop schedule.
Now, once you've identified all the
details of individual activities,
now we can figure out how long the entire
project is going to take.
And that's really what the developed
schedule refers to.
Right, one of the key tools is a critical
path method, right?
Again, which is covered in, in separate
videos.
In fact, all of the important tools and
techniques are covered in separate videos.
The key output is the Schedule Baseline.
This baseline, this is, remember this
three baselines.
We've got the scope baseline, Schedule
baseline, cost baseline.
So one of the key outputs here is going to
be the Schedule baseline.
And then, finally,
throughout the project, we're
going to be monitoring,
controlling our schedule.
We're monitoring and controlling our
schedule.
Making sure then either we're ahead of
schedule or behind schedule.
Making sure that we're on schedule.
If we're behind schedule, how do we get
back on schedule?
It's good to be ahead
of schedule, but it's
not always possible to
be ahead of schedule.
More than likely our project ends up going
behind schedule.
So that's what we want to try and avoid.
And that's what control schedule is.
Monitoring controlling
the schedule, managing
changes to any of the
baselines and so and so forth.
In this case, managing changes to the
schedule, to the schedule baseline.
So, one of the key outputs then of
control, now, of any monitoring
controlling process, what
we're doing in monitoring
control and we're comparing
actual results to our plan.
This is what we've accomplished,
this is what we should have accomplished.
Why is there a discrepancy?
And that's what work performance
information refers to.
The information, remember, is it
interpretation.
Are we head a schedule or behind schedule,
right?
in this case.
So we need our work performance data.
So that's a consideration.
Workformist data is from executing.
That's our raw observation.
And then we compare it with our plan.
So our workforce data might say,
we finished this activity on this date.
Our plan would say we should have finished
it on this other date.
And so our information
interpretation is, well, we
either were ahead of schedule
or we're behind schedule.
And again, these tools
and techniques, they're
all covered in in separate videos as well.
All right.
So, so these are, there's just a summary
then, a quick summary
of all of these ITTOs.
Again, don't sit down and memorize them.
Just have a decent understanding of them.
Okay.